<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Riddim Yard</title>
    <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riddim Yard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:tahoma,verdana,arial,helvetica,bitstream vera sans,sans-serif; font-size:12px"&gt; is the home of foundation Jamaican music: Ska, Rocksteady, Deejay, Dub, Roots &amp;amp; Dancehall &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:tahoma,verdana,arial,helvetica,bitstream vera sans,sans-serif; font-size:12px"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:tahoma,verdana,arial,helvetica,bitstream vera sans,sans-serif; font-size:12px"&gt;email: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:rick_howe@hotmail.com" rel="nofollow" style='color: rgb(204, 34, 41); text-decoration-line: none; font-weight: bold; font-family: Tahoma, Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, "Bitstream Vera Sans", sans-serif; font-size: 12px;' target="_blank"&gt;rickhowe@riddimyard.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <category>Roots, dub and rocksteady</category>
    <image>
      <url>https://amrap-pages-image.s3.amazonaws.com/profile/6931.jpg</url>
      <title>Riddim Yard</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>La Cabra</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-10-10/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Masicka delivers lyrical precision and confidence on &lt;em&gt;La Cabra&lt;/em&gt; – Spanish for &lt;em&gt;The Goat&lt;/em&gt; – reinforcing his claim to greatness with razor-sharp wordplay and heavyweight production. Plus Popcaan's new drop &lt;em&gt;Proving&lt;/em&gt;, a tough street tune laced with his trademark flow and attitude, showing the Unruly Boss in commanding form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also pay tribute to Alton Ellis on the anniversary of his passing – the soulful pioneer who helped shape rocksteady, and the very language of Jamaican music. His influence continues to echo through every generation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-10-10+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-10-10/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-10-10</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singers &amp; Players from Roberto Sanchez's Lone Ark</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-10-17/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years, Roberto Sánchez has stood among &lt;strong&gt;Riddim Yard’s top producers&lt;/strong&gt; – a master of live-tape, analogue roots reggae whose A-Lone Ark Muzik Studio in Santander keeps the spirit of the 70s alive. But it’s not just his mixing board skills – &lt;strong&gt;his vocal work and harmony arrangements have long been a Riddim Yard favourite&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now he steps forward on the mic with &lt;em&gt;Singers &amp;amp; Players&lt;/em&gt; – nine conscious and spiritual songs voiced over heavyweight riddims from his own band &lt;strong&gt;Message&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another crew that gets regular rotation on Riddim Yard, the French sound system collective &lt;strong&gt;Stand High Patrol&lt;/strong&gt; return with &lt;em&gt;Underground Oasis&lt;/em&gt; – a deep, dubbed-out journey that blends roots and electronic textures in their unmistakably fresh, original and creative style. Forever pushing the boundaries of modern dub while keeping the culture at the core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus new Afrobeats from Burna Boy off the back of his first ever Australian show in Melbourne last night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-10-17+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-10-17/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-10-17</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go Deh Yaka</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-10-24/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week on Riddim Yard: 80s funk-reggae from Brooklyn group &lt;strong&gt;Monyaka&lt;/strong&gt; and their album &lt;em&gt;Reggaenomics&lt;/em&gt; - plus lesser-known gems from &lt;strong&gt;Dennis Brown&lt;/strong&gt;, produced by &lt;strong&gt;Bunny Gemini&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;Record Factory&lt;/strong&gt; label. Also 90s dancehall from &lt;strong&gt;Charlie Chaplin&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Josey Wales&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;King of the Dancehall&lt;/em&gt;), and roots from &lt;strong&gt;Delroy Williams&lt;/strong&gt; with his 1982 album &lt;em&gt;I Stand Black&lt;/em&gt; - produced by &lt;strong&gt;Augustus Pablo&lt;/strong&gt; for the &lt;strong&gt;Message&lt;/strong&gt; label.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-10-24+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-10-24/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-10-24</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Vivian Jones</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-10-31/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Hurricane Melissa that devistated Jamaica this week, we pay tribute to Jamaican born British reggae singer Vivian Jones who passed away in London this week aged 68. Better known for his contribution to the creation of the Lovers Rock genre, but Riddim Yard focusses on his Roots gems from the 80s to today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus late 80s dancehall on the Skengdon label with singers like Gregory Isaacs and Junior Delgado, and brand new dancehall from Jahvillani.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-10-31+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-10-31/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-10-31</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubled World</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-11-07/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brand new European releases from some Riddim Yard favourites.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new 7-inch from one of Riddim Yard’s favourite reggae crews. On &lt;em&gt;Troubled World&lt;/em&gt;, world-class rub-a-dub singer &lt;strong&gt;Peter Youthman&lt;/strong&gt; steps forward with a powerful vocal cut produced by William Spring for his consistently killer &lt;strong&gt;Roll &amp;amp; Record&lt;/strong&gt; label in &lt;strong&gt;France.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus killer rocksteady revival from Riddim Yard favourites &lt;strong&gt;Adubta and Marcus I&lt;/strong&gt;. Think vintage rocksteady with a twist of Lee 'Scratch' Perry Black Ark. Fire from Europe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in the mix: &lt;strong&gt;A Wicked Combination - Fruits Records &amp;amp; Roberto Sánchez in Dub Style. &lt;/strong&gt;Spanish engineer Roberto Sánchez has long been one of the top producers featured on the show, and Swiss label Fruits Records is one of the finest labels in modern roots and dub. Roberto mixed the original vocal cuts himself years back, and now he’s taken those same sessions and turned them into a full dub showcase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-11-07+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-11-07/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-07</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buju back to his best</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-11-14/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buju Banton&lt;/strong&gt; is back to his best on a rugged brand new dancehall shot &lt;strong&gt;Hard Ears&lt;/strong&gt; on Gargamel Music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, a deep crate gem out of &lt;strong&gt;Boston Massachusetts&lt;/strong&gt; - rare 80s roots from &lt;strong&gt;Healin’ Of The Nations&lt;/strong&gt;, a cult-status band whose indie pressings became treasured by roots collectors worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus some foundation cuts in the mix: classic rocksteady from &lt;strong&gt;The Hamlins&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Studio One&lt;/strong&gt;, sweet harmonies and timeless Coxsone magic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-11-14+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-11-14/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-14</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rich Inna Farin - Chronic Law blazing hot</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-11-21/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three fresh cuts from one of Riddim Yard's favourite modern dancehall artists, the ever-prolific &lt;strong&gt;Chronic Law&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Rumours&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Big A&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Rich Inna Farin&lt;/em&gt; bringing that signature Law Boss energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heavyweight roots selections from &lt;strong&gt;Yabby You&lt;/strong&gt; with Jamaican saxophone king &lt;strong&gt;Tommy McCook&lt;/strong&gt;, drawing from the classic &lt;em&gt;Blazing Horns&lt;/em&gt; album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus deep cultural fire from &lt;strong&gt;Burning Spear&lt;/strong&gt;, featuring two powerful tracks off his 1980 album &lt;em&gt;Hail H.I.M.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-11-21+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-11-21/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-21</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Jimmy Cliff</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-11-28/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A tribute to reggae legend and Jamaican cultural icon &lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Cliff&lt;/strong&gt;, who passed away this week at the age of 81. A master songwriter with nuff crossover hits, but Riddim Yard shines a light on his early ska recordings and some of the lesser-known gems that shaped his foundation years. We also revisit the soundtrack to &lt;em&gt;The Harder They Come&lt;/em&gt; - the 1972 film that introduced global audiences to Kingston’s struggles, spirit and music culture, and helped cement Cliff as one of reggae’s defining voices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s brand new up-to-the-times dancehall from &lt;strong&gt;Vybz Kartel&lt;/strong&gt;, the Wurl Boss himself, with his fiery new single &lt;em&gt;Guapi&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-11-28+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-11-28/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-28</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special guest Stranger Cole</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-05/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahead of his Australian tour, ska pioneer &lt;strong&gt;Stranger Cole&lt;/strong&gt; returns to the Riddim Yard studio eight years on from his 2017 visit. He joins us alongside &lt;strong&gt;Jane Hilson&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Miss SkaTonic&lt;/strong&gt;, ahead of their show supporting Stranger Cole, backed by &lt;strong&gt;The Ska Vendors&lt;/strong&gt;, at the Brunswick Ballroom on Saturday 13 December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, it's war season in dancehall. &lt;strong&gt;Masicka has Tommy Lee Sparta in his sights&lt;/strong&gt;, firing off two new savage diss tracks. This one could get ugly...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-12-05+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-05/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>War season</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-12/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;War season continues as the feud between Tommy Lee Sparta and Masicka heats up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dancehall war season is in full swing, with the feud between &lt;strong&gt;Tommy Lee Sparta&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Masicka&lt;/strong&gt; now entering its second week and showing no signs of slowing down. The exchanges have been fierce, tactical and deeply personal, with both artists pushing the lyrical stakes higher each round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus &lt;strong&gt;Chronic Law&lt;/strong&gt; returns with &lt;strong&gt;Badness Upgrade 2.0&lt;/strong&gt; - the sequel to &lt;em&gt;Badness Upgrade&lt;/em&gt; and one of the biggest tunes of the year on Riddim Yard in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-12-12+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-12/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-12-12</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-19/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Riddim Yard’s Best of 2025 show brings together the records that defined the year on the program, led by an easy and unanimous pick for album of the year. Lila Iké takes top honours with her debut album &lt;em&gt;The Treasure Self Love&lt;/em&gt;. No surprise here - Lila Iké has been the number one artist on Riddim Yard for over five years straight, and in 2025 she released a debut that lived up to that run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Best of 2025 selection is based purely on personal taste and what actually connected on the show throughout the year. Riddim Yard isn’t beholden to record labels, PR campaigns or promoters, which makes this a genuinely independent and unique list shaped by weekly listening, repeat plays and real response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2025 was also a strong year for European roots and dub. France’s Stand High Patrol continued to push their unmistakable sound system energy, while Roll &amp;amp; Record linked with the legendary Peter Youthman for heavyweight cuts that bridged classic roots spirit with contemporary production. Standing above it all on the production side was Roberto Sanchez, the number one current producer on Riddim Yard this year, delivering a full-length vocal album and a full dub LP on Fruits Records, both in heavy rotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year also belonged to Marcus I and aDUBta, whose steady stream of releases once again proved why they are one of the most consistent modern roots and dub partnerships around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the modern dancehall front, Chronic Law was the most played artist on the show in 2025, dominating playlists with his sharp delivery and relentless output. Alongside him, there was no shortage of heat from Vybz Kartel, Masicka and Skeng, keeping Riddim Yard firmly locked into the current pulse of dancehall while staying true to its foundations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Best of 2025 edition is a snapshot of a year that balanced roots, dub and modern dancehall - from debut albums to sound system anthems - all selected from the records that mattered most on Riddim Yard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-12-19+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-19/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-12-19</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>