<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Riddim Yard</title>
    <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riddim Yard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:tahoma,verdana,arial,helvetica,bitstream vera sans,sans-serif; font-size:12px"&gt; is the home of foundation Jamaican music: Ska, Rocksteady, Deejay, Dub, Roots &amp;amp; Dancehall &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:tahoma,verdana,arial,helvetica,bitstream vera sans,sans-serif; font-size:12px"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:tahoma,verdana,arial,helvetica,bitstream vera sans,sans-serif; font-size:12px"&gt;email: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:rick_howe@hotmail.com" rel="nofollow" style='color: rgb(204, 34, 41); text-decoration-line: none; font-weight: bold; font-family: Tahoma, Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, "Bitstream Vera Sans", sans-serif; font-size: 12px;' target="_blank"&gt;rickhowe@riddimyard.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <category>Roots, dub and rocksteady</category>
    <image>
      <url>https://amrap-pages-image.s3.amazonaws.com/profile/6931.jpg</url>
      <title>Riddim Yard</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Best of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-19/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Riddim Yard’s Best of 2025 show brings together the records that defined the year on the program, led by an easy and unanimous pick for album of the year. Lila Iké takes top honours with her debut album &lt;em&gt;The Treasure Self Love&lt;/em&gt;. No surprise here - Lila Iké has been the number one artist on Riddim Yard for over five years straight, and in 2025 she released a debut that lived up to that run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Best of 2025 selection is based purely on personal taste and what actually connected on the show throughout the year. Riddim Yard isn’t beholden to record labels, PR campaigns or promoters, which makes this a genuinely independent and unique list shaped by weekly listening, repeat plays and real response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2025 was also a strong year for European roots and dub. France’s Stand High Patrol continued to push their unmistakable sound system energy, while Roll &amp;amp; Record linked with the legendary Peter Youthman for heavyweight cuts that bridged classic roots spirit with contemporary production. Standing above it all on the production side was Roberto Sanchez, the number one current producer on Riddim Yard this year, delivering a full-length vocal album and a full dub LP on Fruits Records, both in heavy rotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year also belonged to Marcus I and aDUBta, whose steady stream of releases once again proved why they are one of the most consistent modern roots and dub partnerships around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the modern dancehall front, Chronic Law was the most played artist on the show in 2025, dominating playlists with his sharp delivery and relentless output. Alongside him, there was no shortage of heat from Vybz Kartel, Masicka and Skeng, keeping Riddim Yard firmly locked into the current pulse of dancehall while staying true to its foundations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Best of 2025 edition is a snapshot of a year that balanced roots, dub and modern dancehall - from debut albums to sound system anthems - all selected from the records that mattered most on Riddim Yard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-12-19+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-19/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-12-19</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDGAF</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-26/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The final Riddim Yard show of 2025&lt;/strong&gt; closes out the year with fresh, up-to-the-times dancehall. Aidonia checks in with &lt;strong&gt;IDGAF&lt;/strong&gt;, his new hard-edged flute riddim produced by &lt;strong&gt;Chimney Records&lt;/strong&gt;, delivering trademark attitude and confidence. Also on rotation, &lt;strong&gt;Govana – Pond Turtle&lt;/strong&gt;, riding the &lt;strong&gt;WYFL riddim&lt;/strong&gt; built by &lt;strong&gt;DJ Mac &amp;amp; Crash Dummy&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the hottest instrumentals in dancehall right now. Plus two big street records: &lt;strong&gt;Boy Boy – Rum Chat&lt;/strong&gt; from the Tinibad camp, and &lt;strong&gt;Skillibeng – City&lt;/strong&gt;, another sharp statement from one of dancehall’s most dominant voices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2025-12-26+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2025-12-26/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-12-26</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enemy State</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-02/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kicking off 2026 with a mix of current dancehall tensions and timeless soulful cuts. &lt;strong&gt;Jahshii&lt;/strong&gt; lands right in the middle of the ongoing clash between Tommy Lee Sparta and Masicka, delivering a sharp diss on Enemy State. Also in the mix, new dancehall from &lt;strong&gt;Teejay&lt;/strong&gt; with Amount Ah, a confident, street-focused release continuing his steady run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balancing the heat, we dip into dreamy soul-disco sides from &lt;strong&gt;Studio One&lt;/strong&gt;, spotlighting singers like &lt;strong&gt;Otis Gayle &lt;/strong&gt;and &lt;strong&gt;Willie Williams&lt;/strong&gt; and that smooth, late-night summer sound. Plus a modern lovers rock touch with a track from &lt;strong&gt;The Far East&lt;/strong&gt;’s 2020 album &lt;strong&gt;NY Is For Lovers&lt;/strong&gt;, connecting classic romance to a contemporary global reggae feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that on the first Riddim Yard of 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2026-01-02+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-02/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2026-01-02</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Herpes Takeover </title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-09/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week on Riddim Yard the Studio One women are representing with rocksteady cuts from Marcia Griffiths &amp;amp; Hortense Ellis on classic Coxsone productions. The foundation run continued with early Wailers sides from Studio One, including their cover of a Bob Dylan classic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Followed by Mellow Yellow and Young Ranks and their 1983 album &lt;em&gt;Herpes Takeover&lt;/em&gt;, a wicked deejay combination session that captures dancehall right as it was finding its modern voice. Then fast-forwarding into the digital dancehall era with killer 80s King Kong selections that still sound raw and futuristic today. Plus brand new up to the times dancehall from the 1Lawboss: Chronic Law.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2026-01-09+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-09/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2026-01-09</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FREE 1LawBoss</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-16/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most prolific artist in modern dancehall, &lt;strong&gt;Chronic Law&lt;/strong&gt;, is currently in the custody of US immigration authorities (ICE). Officials have not disclosed the reason for his detention, nor where he is being held, but the 1LawBoss is still well represented as always on Riddim Yard this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also brand new music from &lt;strong&gt;Protoje&lt;/strong&gt;, linking up once again with &lt;strong&gt;Damian ‘Jr Gong’ Marley&lt;/strong&gt;. At We Feet is the third single from Protoje’s upcoming full-length album, due in 2026 on Ineffable Records in conjunction with In.Digg.Nation Collective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we head to &lt;strong&gt;Mamadawerre&lt;/strong&gt;, a remote outstation in &lt;strong&gt;Arnhem Land&lt;/strong&gt;, for &lt;strong&gt;Indigenous desert reggae &lt;/strong&gt;in the&lt;strong&gt; Kunwinjku language &lt;/strong&gt;from&lt;strong&gt; Wildflower,&lt;/strong&gt; before travelling around 250km west of Alice Springs to &lt;strong&gt;Ikuntji&lt;/strong&gt;, home of the &lt;strong&gt;Tjintu Desert Band&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2026-01-16+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-16/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2026-01-16</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Rob Hirst from Midnight Oil</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-23/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two brand new 45s  from Fruits Records, both backed by Swiss studio crew The 18th Parallel. Earl Sixteen links with them on &lt;strong&gt;My Son&lt;/strong&gt;, a roots tune about the pressures facing young people, with a dub version from Westfinga on the flip. Alongside that is &lt;strong&gt;More Work To Be Done&lt;/strong&gt; from Young Kulcha, a sound system favourite in Europe, again paired with a Westfinga dub cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also a dedication to Stephen ‘Cat’ Coore from Third World, revisiting one of the band’s most powerful and politically charged songs, &lt;strong&gt;96 Degrees In The Shade&lt;/strong&gt;. The song tells the story of Paul Bogle and the Morant Bay Rebellion of 1865, when Bogle led an uprising against injustice and colonial rule, later becoming a Jamaican National Hero whose image appears on the Jamaican 10 cent coin. It’s a reminder that Third World’s roots catalogue was never just about vibes, but about history, resistance and real Jamaican stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, a deeply personal tribute to &lt;strong&gt;Midnight Oil drummer&lt;/strong&gt; and songwriter &lt;strong&gt;Rob Hirst&lt;/strong&gt;. There is no songwriter who has had a more profound effect on my life than Rob Hirst, and songs like &lt;strong&gt;The Dead Heart&lt;/strong&gt; completely shaped my worldview as a child. Midnight Oil taught me that white Australia has a Blak history. Dancing to the Oils with my family are some of my earliest memories. These shall not be Forgotten Years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2026-01-23+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-23/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2026-01-23</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tribute to Sly Dunbar</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-30/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week on Riddim Yard we pay tribute to the legendary Lowell ‘Sly’ Dunbar, one of the most influential drummers in the history of reggae. From roots and dub to dancehall and beyond, Sly’s timing, feel and invention helped define entire eras of Jamaican music, whether as part of the unstoppable Sly &amp;amp; Robbie partnership or as the driving force behind countless classic recordings. This week’s program celebrates a musician whose impact is impossible to overstate and whose rhythms will live on forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2026-01-30+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-01-30/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2026-01-30</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sun is shining, Dennis Brown is sweet</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-02-06/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week on Riddim Yard we’re celebrating &lt;strong&gt;Dennis Brown Week&lt;/strong&gt;, marking the Crown Prince’s birthday on February 1, 1957. From his teenage Studio One breakthroughs to his roots and international classics, we’ll be saluting &lt;strong&gt;the greatest singer of all time&lt;/strong&gt; and revisiting key moments from his remarkable career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll also be featuring the brand new &lt;strong&gt;Ronnie Davis&lt;/strong&gt; release &lt;strong&gt;Sun Is Shining&lt;/strong&gt; - a project &lt;strong&gt;50 years in the making&lt;/strong&gt;, originally voiced for Bunny “Striker” Lee and now finally brought to life with Prince Fatty’s world-class dub touch. A fresh update on a roots classic, linking generations in serious style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, new music from &lt;strong&gt;Marcus I meets aDUBta &amp;amp; The Black Oak Roots Allstars&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;Upful&lt;/strong&gt;, the first single from their upcoming album &lt;em&gt;Fullness&lt;/em&gt;, out March 13, 2026 - pure upful vibes, just as the title suggests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we’ll be checking in with the latest dancehall from &lt;strong&gt;Skeng&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Govana&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Chronic Law&lt;/strong&gt;, including an update on Chronic Law’s situation, with reports he’s currently being held at the Florida facility dubbed “Alligator Alcatraz.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2026-02-06+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-02-06/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2026-02-06</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robert Nesta tribute and new Wurl Boss</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-02-13/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reggae Month rolls on with a tribute to the late king &lt;strong&gt;Bob Marley&lt;/strong&gt; - digging into early Wailers cuts and rarer tunes from the pre-&lt;strong&gt;Island Records&lt;/strong&gt; era, before the global breakthrough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rare early productions from &lt;strong&gt;Lloyd Barnes&lt;/strong&gt; - long before the Wackie’s era - on the Senrab and Aries labels. Cuts like &lt;strong&gt;John Clarke&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Wasn’t It You&lt;/em&gt; (not to be confused with &lt;strong&gt;Johnny Clarke&lt;/strong&gt;) and the knockout deejay cut &lt;em&gt;Thriller in Manilla&lt;/em&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Jah Tuff&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus brand new, right-now dancehall from &lt;strong&gt;Vybz Kartel&lt;/strong&gt;. Kartel finally jumps on the hottest riddim in dancehall, the &lt;strong&gt;WYFL riddim&lt;/strong&gt; by Crashdummy &amp;amp; DJ Mac, alongside a killer deep-voice cut, &lt;strong&gt;Hype Life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2026-02-13+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-02-13/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2026-02-13</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Lone Ark pre-releases</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-02-20/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week on Riddim Yard, we feature three exclusive pre-release cuts from Spanish roots heavyweight Roberto Sánchez, giving listeners an early taste of what’s coming next on vinyl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up was &lt;strong&gt;Errol 'Flabba' Holt - Roots Man Skankin’&lt;/strong&gt;, featuring the legendary bassist from The Roots Radics. One of the most played bass players on the show, Flabba also proves here that he’s got a strong, soulful singing voice to match his legendary status on the instrument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next came &lt;strong&gt;Robbie Ark - Forward To Zion&lt;/strong&gt;. Robbie Ark is Roberto Sánchez himself on vocals, and once again he delivers soulful harmonies and beautifully layered arrangements. As always, Rick showed love for Robbie’s voice and his consistently high-level vocal production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rounding out the roots selections was &lt;strong&gt;Ranking Joe - Marcus Garvey&lt;/strong&gt;, from one of reggae’s great veteran deejays. Decades into his career, Ranking Joe is still sounding sharp, conscious, and powerful - proof that true foundation artists never lose their touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show also dipped into classic UK roots with 1980s material from &lt;strong&gt;Black Roots&lt;/strong&gt;, representing St Pauls in Bristol - a key hub of Jamaican diaspora culture following the Windrush generation. Their music reflects the deep roots connections between Bristol and Jamaica, and the role reggae played in shaping Black British identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the contemporary tip, there was new dancehall heat from &lt;strong&gt;Chronic Law&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;Glock Fi The Team&lt;/strong&gt;. Chronic Law was arrested in the United States in late 2025 and remains in custody at the Florida immigration facility sometimes referred to as 'Alligator Alcatraz'. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;International flavours came through with a stop in West Africa, featuring music from &lt;strong&gt;Beta Simon&lt;/strong&gt; out of &lt;strong&gt;Côte d'Ivoire&lt;/strong&gt;, highlighting the long-standing influence of reggae and Rastafari culture across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2026-02-20+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-02-20/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2026-02-20</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Likkle Jordee Spotlight, Phil Pratt Tribute &amp; WYFL Riddim Heat</title>
      <link>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-02-27/11-00-00</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="flex flex-col text-sm pb-25"&gt;
&lt;div class="text-base my-auto mx-auto pb-10 [--thread-content-margin:--spacing(4)] @w-sm/main:[--thread-content-margin:--spacing(6)] @w-lg/main:[--thread-content-margin:--spacing(16)] px-(--thread-content-margin)"&gt;
&lt;div class="[--thread-content-max-width:40rem] @w-lg/main:[--thread-content-max-width:48rem] mx-auto max-w-(--thread-content-max-width) flex-1 group/turn-messages focus-visible:outline-hidden relative flex w-full min-w-0 flex-col agent-turn"&gt;
&lt;div class="flex max-w-full flex-col grow"&gt;
&lt;div class="min-h-8 text-message relative flex w-full flex-col items-end gap-2 text-start break-words whitespace-normal [.text-message+&amp;amp;]:mt-1" dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;div class="flex w-full flex-col gap-1 empty:hidden first:pt-[1px]"&gt;
&lt;div class="markdown prose dark:prose-invert w-full wrap-break-word dark markdown-new-styling"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week on Riddim Yard we spotlight Likkle Jordee, a Native Hawaiian singer with serious reggae sensibilities. We feature the immaculate vibes of his new lovers rock single ‘Moonlight’, then reach back to his earlier work with Ooklah The Moc, selecting cuts from their 2008 album &lt;em&gt;Vaults&lt;/em&gt; - a key chapter in modern Hawaiian reggae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pay tribute to Phil Pratt, one of the quiet architects of rocksteady and early roots reggae. Through his Sunshot label he crafted some of the darkest, most disciplined rhythms of the era. Dennis Brown’s ‘Let Love In’ remains a certified Riddim Yard favourite - deep, minor-key and built to last - a reminder of Pratt’s subtle but heavyweight influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus we dive into the WYFL Riddim - the hottest riddim in Jamaica, dominating dancehalls since late 2025. Featuring &lt;strong&gt;Mavado&lt;/strong&gt; with ‘Bad and Bomboclaat Rich’ and &lt;strong&gt;Anthony B&lt;/strong&gt; with ‘Box Ah Rubbaz’, produced by DJ MAC and CrashDummy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="z-0 flex min-h-[46px] justify-start"&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="mt-3 w-full empty:hidden"&gt;
&lt;div class="text-center"&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="pointer-events-none h-px w-px absolute bottom-0"&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <author>Rick Howe</author>
      <enclosure url="https://airnet.org.au/omnystudio/3pbs/riddim-yard/2026-02-27+11:00:00/aac_mid.m4a" type="audio/mp4"/>
      <guid>https://www.pbsfm.org.au/program/riddim-yard/2026-02-27/11-00-00</guid>
      <pubDate>2026-02-27</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>